<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
	<properties>
		<title>Known Issues / Experienced Problems</title>
		<author>Thomas</author>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<section name="Known issues">
		
			<subsection name="Application only works locally">
				<ol>
					<li>
						Everytime new feature should be tested in the local environment. In order to do so, the devserver 
						comes with the appengine maven plugin is used. Starting the server in the commandline with the command 
						<b>mvn appengine:devserver</b> starts the server which can then be accessed in the web browser of choice 
						by invoking <i>http://localhost:8080</i>. Since we are testing a webservice, 
						<i>http://localhost:8080/BookServiceService</i> has to be called using SoapUI 
						(<a href="http://soapui.org/">SoapUI homepage</a>).
					</li>
					<li>
						Even if the service works on the devserver, it is not guaranteed that it also works after uploading 
						it to google app engine using <b>mvn appengine:update</b>. Therefore, it is important to test the functionality 
						immediately after uploading a new version of the service. If the requests to 
						<i>https://theuniversalwebservice.appspot.com/BookServiceService</i> are not working anymore, the following 
						steps can be undertaken: 
						<ul>
							<li>Remove all installed maven jars in the .m2 folder. This can solve the issue of interfering 
							dependencies. After removing the content on the folder, rerun <i>mvn clean install</i> which 
							triggers the new installation of only needed dependencies.</li>
							<li>If no further steps help, check the versions of the service on 
							<a href="https://appengine.google.com/">https://appengine.google.com/</a>. Set another version as default 
							and delete the old version. After that rerun <i>mvn clean install</i>.</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
				</ol>
			</subsection>
			<!--  
			<p>
				<img alt="BookGrabber_Classdiagramm" src="images/bookgrabber_cd.png"
					width="100%" />
			</p>
			-->
		</section>
	</body>
</document>

